EUro*pass* Curriculum Vitae Alexia Mifsud Vassallo



# Alexia Mifsud Vassallo



- No.51, "Capri", Island Street, Birzebbuga BBG1764, MALTA.
- lexvassallo@gmail.com

Gender Female | Date of birth 02/09/1983 | Nationality Maltese

## Motivation for the Application

Throughout my past 13 year career at MFSA & 10 of which within the Banking Supervision Unit, I must say that I have cultivated further my experience, knowhow & knowledge & do feel that it is time to boost up my profession & take it to the next level. I do hold a good insight of the banking sector operations, functions & modus operandi, which I acquired through the multiple roles & exposures that I was assigned to within the Banking Supervision Unit over these past years, ranging from off- & on-site supervision of both financial & credit institutions, BRRD implementation including Recovery Plans' assessment amongst others.

Moreover, I have been part of the Ongoing team since November 2018, whereby I have the responsibility of supervising 2 LSIs. Moreover being the leader of stress testing analysis, I have the duty to coordinate & plan this task as part of the SREP process. I have been involved in stress tests from different legal & operational frameworks & must say from the inception of this risk measurement tool, including the EBA exercises of LSIs, from a BR/12 standpoint & also from the SL33.09 perspective.

Nonetheless, I do consider myself self-motivated & ready to take up new challenges such that to broaden further my knowledge and work experiences. I am able to multi-task, meet strict deadlines, feel motivated & motivate other team members & also well organised. Nonetheless, I am always eager to enrich further my academic and operational knowledge, hence consider myself available to attend courses and training as deemed best.

Whilst hoping that you find my CV of interest, I look forward to attend any interviews if need be, while in case you do require further information or clarifications from my end, kindly revert back.

Curriculum Vitae Alexia Mifsud Vassallo

# WORK EXPERIENCE

euro*pass* 

# (October 2008 – Till Date) on Reduced Hours Basis.

# Financial Analyst at the Banking Supervision Unit at MFSA

<u>Duties:</u> Throughout these past years I have been involved in various tasks within the BSU, arraying from both on-site & off-site supervision & lately also being part of the crisis management team, including recovery plans analysis.

Nonetheless, I have also conducted reports, papers and research studies, enriching further my area of expertise, that of Stress Testing Analysis, basing also my Master's thesis on this topic. In collaboration with the Financial Stability team at the Central Bank of Malta & the EBA we have conducted both micro and macro Stress Tests to analyse the risk resilience of both single institutions & the Maltese Banking System as a whole, always within the EU framework of operations. Main aim is to assist the development & implementation of this new risk management tool within the Maltese Banking industry, in view of the restrictions & limitations faced by our market, considering both the economic, financial & regulatory aspects of this area of study.

#### October 2005 - October 2008

### Clerk & Desk Officer at MFSA

<u>Duties:</u> Initially employed at a clerical level, where my duties included to provide support to desk officers at the Registry of Companies, while upholding day-to-day secretarial duties to the Registrar of Companies. Within 9 months of employment I was promoted as Desk Officer at a managerial grade, where my tasks included mainly the overall maintenance of companies registered in Malta.

#### September 2005 – December 2005

# Research Interviewer at BPC International

<u>Duties</u>: Fieldwork data-collection through the completion of questionnaires. Till now I participated in primary marketing survey types, which were conducted through face-to-face households' interviews.

#### August 2005 – October 2005

### Administration Officer at 3D

 $\underline{\textbf{Duties}} : \textbf{Recruitment of runners, preparation of distribution} - \textbf{schedules, issuing of pay-rolls amongst other clerical tasks}.$ 

#### Summer 2004

## Clerk / Employment Advisor at ETC

<u>Duties</u>: Inputting of new vacancies through network, informing unemployed individuals of present available vacancies and helping them out to apply for such jobs and also taking care of the free-phone.

# Summer 2003

# Clerk / Customer Care Assistant at Enemalta

**Duties:** Helping out clients at the Customer Care Office, registration of electricity services permits and with other clerical duties.

#### Summer 2002

# Skola Sajf Teacher at Ghaxaq Primary School

 $\underline{\textbf{Duties}} : \textbf{Preparation of classroom and outdoor activities like crafts, sports, singing and drama.}$ 

#### Summer 2001

#### Cashier at Fra Martino Restaurant at Corinthia San Gorg

 $\underline{\textbf{Duties}}\text{: Welcoming clients at restaurant, taking reservations, in charge of inputting cash transactions and responsible of cash flow}$ 



Alexia Mifsud Vassallo



# **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

2007 – 2012 MSc Finance & Financial Law (Merit)

MQF Level 7

University of London

2001-2005 Bachelor of Commerce (Hons) in Economics

MQF Level 6

University of Malta

1999-2001 Matriculation Certificate

MQF Level 5

**WRITING** 

C1/C2

C1/C2

Paolino Vassallo Higher Secondary, Cordin

3 subjects at **Advanced Level:** Accounting

Economics Italian

4 subjects at Intermediate Level: Information Technology

Marketing Pure Mathematics Systems of Knowledge

9 subjects at Ordinary Level: Accounting

Economics
English
French
Italian
Maltese
Mathematics
Physics
Religious Studies.

**SPEAKING** 

#### PERSONAL SKILLS

#### Mother tongue(s) Mal

Italian

Maltese & English

Replace with language	Listening	Reading	Spoken interaction	Spoken production		
	C1/C2	C1/C2	C1/C2	C1/C2		
	Replace with name of language certificate. Enter level if known.					

Replace with language C1/C2 C1/C2 C1/C2 C1/C2

**UNDERSTANDING** 

Replace with name of language certificate. Enter level if known.

Levels: A1/A2: Basic user - B1/B2: Independent user - C1/C2 Proficient user Common European Framework of Reference for Languages

#### Communication skills

- Good communication skills gained through my working experience
- Capable of preparing qualitative & quantitative reports & other working/ technical documents for the benefits of the team/ unit.
- Able to set working systems to ease the sharing & concentration of information & work findings

# Organisational / managerial skills

• Feel comfortable working within a team.

#### Job-related skills

 Have the necessary insight of technical requirements & moreover eager to take up the necessary training to enrich further my knowledge & knowhow with relevance to my job requirements.



Alexia Mifsud Vassallo



#### Digital skills

SELF-ASSESSMENT							
Information processing	Communication	Content creation	Safety	Problem solving			
INDEPENDENT USER	INDEPENDENT USER	INDEPENDENT USER	INDEPENDENT USER	INDEPENDENT USER			

Levels: Basic user - Independent user - Proficient user <u>Digital competences - Self-assessment grid</u>

#### Replace with name of ICT-certificates

good command of office suite (word processor, spread sheet, presentation software)

#### Other skills

As a crafter & artist, it is my passion to create handmade items, from jewellery to cards, wedding invites, souvenirs, home decorations and bespoke venue decorations. Crocheting is one of my favourite mediums & I try as much as possible to embed this skill in many of my creations, whereby my ambition is to further infuse the usage of such delicate medium in fashion wear & accessories. I do take part in Artisan Markets and also had the opportunity to judge at diverse craft competitions. In relation to this, I am also the founder and owner of a small Business, which goes by the name of "Lexy Creations".

#### **Driving licence**

B

#### ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

# Conferences, Seminars & Working Groups

MS Excel Advanced Course, (December 2018).

Seminar on "Current & Best Practices in Recovery Plan Assessment" by ESE, Vienna, Austria, (June 2018).

Seminar on "Recovery Plan Assessment & Analysis" by ESE, Amsterdam, Holland, (June 2016).

Part of the MFSA Crowdfunding Working Group, (2015 till date).

On Site Banking Supervision, Bundesbank, Berlin, Germany, (April 2012).

EBA Stress-test Meetings, London, UK, (2011 - 2012).

EIE Seminar on 2011 Post Crisis Capital & Risk Management, Malta, (April-May 2011).

MFSA Special Training by BaFin, Malta, (January 2011).

Stress-Test Seminar by OSFI Canada, Malta, (January 2010).

Course in Basic German for Beginners, Malta, (January 2010).

Advanced Seminar on ICAAP & Stress-Testing, Eltville, Germany, (July 2009).

MITC Seminar on Basel II: ICAAP Framework, Malta, (June 2009).

BIS Seminar on Stress-Testing, Basel, Switzerland, (October 2009).

IFS CERTIFICATE in English for Banking & Finance, Malta, (April-June 2009).

BIS Conference on Risk Management & Supervision, Basel, Switzerland, (November 2008).

 $IFS\,Seminar\,on\,Enterprise\,Risk\,Management\,(ERM)\,Basel\,II\,Focus,\,Malta\,,\,(April-June\,2008).$ 

Company Law Course, Malta, (October 2006).

### Memberships

Member of the Malta Institute of Professional Photographers

# Other courses

MPS Basic Photography Course - MERIT

MIPP Still Image Photography Course (at MQF Level 3) - PASS

Course in Crochet Lace (at MQF Level 1) - GRADE A

Course in Interior Design & Decoration Level 1 at MCAST - DISTINCTION

Intermediate Flower Art Course by Ms. Nadine M. Grimaud

Achievements in **Pianoforte Playing & Theory** (Grades 1-5)